humana-military.com 2006-12-12

# 

|   
| [](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.humana-military.com&sealid=101)                      **Internet Privacy Statement**  
| Humana Military Healthcare Services, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This Internet privacy statement applies only to information on [http://www.humana-military.com](http://www.humana-military.com/).  
| 

TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this website wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe mark, this website has agreed to notify you of:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you through the website
  2. The organization collecting the information
  3. How the information is used
  4. With whom the information may be shared
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under Humana Military control
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact the HMHS Privacy Office, 500 West Main Street, Louisville, KY 40202 by postal mail or [hmhsprivacyoffice@humana.com](mailto:hmhsprivacyoffice@humana.com) by email. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at [http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php](http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the website to resolve your concerns.  
  
|    
| 

**_Commitment to Confidentiality  
_**At Humana Military Healthcare Services, Inc. (HMHS), we are committed to maintaining the highest level of confidentiality regarding all of the information we receive from our policy owners, including the information obtained from this Web site.

This Privacy Statement will assure you that the information you share with HMHS is kept confidential and fully secure. HMHS may change this Privacy Statement at any time by prominently posting revisions to our Web site although, you will be notified of any modifications in the use of Personally Identifiable Information via email, mail or phone depending on circumstances.  
  
|    
| 

_**Linkage  
**_As you navigate through our web site, you will find links to other sites. Inclusion of these links does not imply endorsement by our web site, or by Humana Military. You are encouraged to look for and review the privacy policies of any site visited since links found located outside the secured section of our site are provided for convenience purposes only.

HMHS has partnered with third parties and provides linkage to specific sites that offer you additional information and services. In order to access these sites, you must register for and log-in to the Self-Service Center portion of our site. These sites are usually co-branded, meaning that you may see both the HMHS logo and the third parties logo within these third party sites. Users of these sites will be made aware of who is collecting personal information, along with the specific privacy policy that applies to that site prior to providing personal information. HMHS does not have control over our third party partner’s use of your information.  
  
|    
| 

**_Personal Information  
_**Personally Identifiable Information is described as data that is unique to an individual, such as a name, address, telephone number, social security number and date of birth (DOB).

At times, we may request personal information from you through our sites in order to deliver requested materials to you, respond to your questions, or deliver a product or service. Members, physicians, and government partners have the ability to register in a secured area of our Web site in order for us to deliver such products or services. Additional information collected by these sites may include organization names, addresses, group numbers and tax identification numbers. The purpose of the registration is to validate members, providers and government partners requesting access to our secured area. The registration also enables us to tailor the information sent to you. Contact forms are used only to deliver requested materials and respond to your questions.

There are instances in which HMHS might internally use the personal information you voluntarily submit, such as identifying and registering you for the Self-Service Center portion of our site. In addition, we may disclose your personal information (as described below) to our agents, third party partners, affiliates and subsidiaries to enable them to perform certain functions for us.

As a registered user of the Self-Services Center portion of our site, you have the option to change your password and email address after you log-in. In case you forget or misplace your Password, we will use your Reminder Question and Answer to identify you in order to provide this information to you.

The Online Services areas of our site make use Session Cookies. "Session Cookies" are small computer files that remain in your computer's memory and are only used to maintain your secure login session. Session Cookies are not written to your computer’s hard drive. Session Cookies are required to gain access to the secured areas of our site. Access to these secured areas will not be granted if the cookie is rejected. This web site’s cookies are not tied to personally identifiable information.

Information that is automatically logged for the purpose of producing reports containing hit volumes are: Query String, Status, Bytes Sent, User-Agent (Browser Type) and Cookie Referrer. 

Personally Identifiable Information provided to HMHS may be subject to disclosure to judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants or orders.  
  
|    
| 

_**Internal Security Procedures  
**_Security measures within our site are in place to protect against the loss, misuse and/or unauthorized alteration of all information voluntarily supplied by using encryption technology, including Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). This technology encrypts (encoded) information as it passes from your browser to our servers.

Only authorized persons are permitted to access your personal information, and they must abide by security, privacy and confidentiality agreements. However, the nature of the Internet prevents us from guaranteeing the confidentiality of information we receive through the site or via e-mail. Therefore, you may contact us instead by US Mail or via telephone on our toll-free number at 1-800-444-5445.  
  
|    
| 

_**Email  
**_By providing an email address, you are indicating that publications can be sent to your email address. You are not required at any time to submit your email address for the purpose of receiving recurring informational/promotional emails from HMHS and/or third parties. You may opt out of receiving publications via email by changing your Communication Preferences located within our Website or by contacting Customer Service by US Mail or via telephone on our toll-free number at 1-800-444-5445.

Humana Military may use e-mail to communicate with you from time to time. However, these e-mail communications will never include your confidential Personal Health Information. Humana Military also strongly suggests that you never include any confidential information should you ever attempt to contact us via e-mail. In the event you do attempt to send us a question, comment and/or job inquiry via; we will share your correspondence with our Customer Service representatives and those employees or agents most capable of addressing your questions and concerns. Ultimately, we will either discard your communication or, in some cases, archive it. Your email address will not be retained for secondary purposes.  
  
|    
| 

_**Modifications  
**_This Internet Privacy Statement is effective as of July 2000 and was last updated in December 2005. HMHS may change this Privacy Statement at any time by prominently posting revisions to our Web site although, you will be notified of any modifications in the use of Personally Identifiable Information via email, mail or phone depending on circumstances. Future changes will be effective and binding as of posting of the notice; unless a different effective date is specified.  
  
|    
     |  **_Copyright  
_**Copyright and other laws protect all information, content and all other materials offered through the web site. You may not copy or distribute any of these materials without prior written consent from Humana Military Healthcare Services. However, you may print a single copy of the information contained on this site so long as you use these materials for personal, non-commercial use only.

The HMHS Web site is maintained by HMHS, 500 West Main Street, Louisville, KY 40202.  
  
|    
|   
|   
  
|    
| 

© Copyright 2005, Humana Military Healthcare Services Legal Disclaimer
